trafalgar.com 2015-04-19

# Privacy Policy - Terms and Conditions - USA - Trafalgar Tours

**Trafalgar Tours West, Inc.**

**Privacy Policy** ****

Last updated: 9th September 2014 

Contents

Please click on a link below to jump to a specific paragraph:-

1\.  About This Document

2\.  Your Consent

3\.  Copyright Notice

4\.  About Us

5\.  Our Commitment

6\.  Who Our Privacy Policy Covers

7\.  What Laws We Comply With

8\.  What Types Of Personal Data We Process

9\. How We Collect Or Generate Your Personal Data

10\. What Do We Use Your Personal Data For ?

11\. Use Of Your Personal Data For Direct Marketing

12\. Disclosure Of Your Personal Data

13\. How Third Parties Will Handle Your Personal Data

14\. Location Of Your Personal Data

15\. Keeping Your Data Secure

16\. How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Data For ?

17\. Your Rights

18\. Changes To This Privacy Policy

19\. Applicable Law And Disputes

1.           About this document

This document states our privacy policy in respect of customer personal data, which will govern the way we process personal data you provide us.  It serves as an expression of our commitment to protecting your private personal information, but is not a contract.  Please see Section 18 below for rights the law provides you in relation to your personal data.

2.           Your consent

By using our websites, providing any personal data to us, or booking any travel services with us, you confirm that you agree to and consent to the terms of this document, to the extent your consent is required by any applicable law.

3.           Copyright notice

This document, and all content of our websites is Copyright© Trafalgar Tours West, Inc. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.

4.           About us

This is the privacy policy of Trafalgar Tours West, Inc. (referred to as " **we** ", " **us** " or " **our** ").  We are incorporated under the laws of California.  Our incorporation address is 801 E. Katella Ave., Anaheim, CA 92805.

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or about how we process your personal data, including any complaints, please contact us either by e-mail to [help@trafalgar.com](mailto:help@trafalgar.com), telephone on 714-937-4900, or by post to 801 E. Katella Ave., Anaheim, California, 92805.

5.           Our commitment

We respect your right to privacy and we aim to ensure you have a trustworthy experience with us, including when using our websites or shops and booking with or through us. We understand many of our customers care about how personal data is used by us, and we want to share with you our policies and practices.   

6.           Who our privacy policy covers

6.1         Our customers

Our privacy policy sets out how we process personal data (including information) relating to individuals who book or enquire about booking travel services with or through us or who are the recipients of any travel services booked with or through us (e.g. you are the passenger for a booking or booking enquiry made by someone else for you), or who are customers or potential customers or recipients of travel services that can be booked with or through us. 

6.2         Examples of who this policy covers

We include in this privacy policy personal data we process relating to: (1) individuals who make an enquiry or booking with us or through us, and individuals in respect of whom any enquiry or booking is made (such as friends, family and tour group members, and officers and employees of businesses and organizations booking with or through us); (2) individuals in respect of whom an enquiry or booking is made with us by an agent; (3) where our customer is a business or organization, employees or individuals who act as representatives of that business or other organization, and individuals connected to that business or other organization, such as owners, partners, shareholders, and directors; and (4) individuals whose personal data comes from other companies in our group (such as where you consented to your personal data being disclosed to other group companies for marketing purposes). 

6.3         When we are data processor only

This privacy policy does not apply where we process personal data as a sub-contractor or data processor on behalf of a third party, and not on our own account.  You must look to that third party and their policy regarding how data in their possession or control is processed.

6.4         Terms used in this policy

When we refer to " **you** " and " **your** " in this privacy policy, we mean any such individual whose personal data we process from time to time. 

When we refer to " **processing** " your personal data, this includes obtaining, recording, storing or holding your personal data, and anything we do with it, such as organizing, adapting or altering it, retrieving, consulting or using it, disclosing it or otherwise making it available to others, combining it with other data, and blocking, erasing or destroying it.

When we refer to " **travel services** " this covers all products and services which may be booked with or through us, such as bespoke vacations, package vacations, accommodation, tours, transport and transfers (whether by air, coach, bus, train, ferry, taxi or other means), car hire, cruises, and charters, and includes both (1) all such products and services which we supply or operate ourselves (including where we sub-contract); and (2) any such products and services provided by a third party which we book for you (acting as agent for you or the third party). Travel services also include any services we or a third party provide in association with travel, such as obtaining visas, foreign exchange, and providing local representatives and support. 

7.           What laws we comply with

We process your personal data in accordance with the following data protection law(s): The Data Protection Act 1998 (which covers protection of personal data generally).

We also seek to comply generally with the laws of the United States in relation to the processing of your personal data. 

8.           What types of personal data we process

This section summarizes the types of personal data about you that we process:-

8.1         Data concerning you as an individual

This includes name, age, photograph, gender, address, telephone, mobile, fax, e-mail, social networking contact details, proofs of identity and address, copies of passports, driving licenses, and utility bills, card and other payment details, and financial information, health information relevant to your planned travel, and travel insurances held, results of searches carried out about you (such as to verify your identity, address, and credit status), your preferences, frequent flyer or travel partner program affiliation and member number, and other information provided to us by or in relation to you which concern you as an individual.

8.2         Business Related Information

If you are an individual associated with a business or other organization that is our customer,  your personal data may include the following information that we link to you: business or organization details (such as name, address, telephone numbers, payment arrangements, financial information, etc.), your relationship with that business or organization (such as owner, partner, director, shareholder, employee, or agent), and your contact details within that business (such as work address, work telephone and mobile numbers, work fax number, and work e-mail address).

8.3         Enquiry and Booking information

Information concerning enquiries and bookings made with or through us for travel services, including where you are making the enquiry or booking or are the recipient of the travel services to which the enquiry or booking relates. This information may include: records of enquiries and searches for vacation and travel products made by or on your behalf, details of your personal interests, needs and other data relevant to your enquiry; details of results, quotes, proposals, estimates and other information given in response to enquiries; details of the vacation, accommodation, travel, car hire, and other travel services booked or enquired about; details of passengers / vacationers traveling; details of the provider of travel services (e.g. tour operator); dates and times of travel; price; payment details (including card details); passport information and visa information; foreign exchange requirements and arrangements; and sensitive information such as health, medical, dietary, mobility, disability, religious or other special conditions or requirements.

8.4         Performance information

Information generated concerning the performance of any booking or other contract made with or through us, including information relating to anything arising during any vacation or other travel services, and information relating to payments to be made. 

8.5         Survey Information

Information collected or generated out of surveys we conduct.

8.6         Competition Information

Information collected or generated out of competitions or promotions we run.

8.7         Account, Registration and Loyalty Information

Information concerning accounts, registrations, or memberships with us, or participation in loyalty programs.

8.8         Correspondence

Correspondence, communications and messages, including between you and us, and between us and third parties, including relating to any booking or booking enquiry, or performance of any contract.

8.9         Website Usage Information

We may collect information about your visits to, browsing of, and use of our website. The range of data we collect will depend on how you interact with our website. 

This information may include: your IP address (a unique identifier allocated to your computer for your connection to the internet); your computer device details (PC, tablet, smartphone, watch, etc.); web browser make and version (e.g. Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Opera, Chrome) you use; operating system (e.g. Windows, Windows Phone, OSX, iOS, Android, Linux, etc); time-zone; browser plug-ins; web-page you came from, identified as referrer web page address by your web browser; cookies; page response times; download error; pages and parts of pages you visit; usage you make of our website, including enquiries and searches undertaken, and registrations for accounts, forums etc.; services and products viewed; length of visit to website and pages; page interaction information (such as scrolling, keys pressed, mouse clicks, touches, and mouse-overs). This will normally be collected and used anonymously, and aggregated for analysis, with your name and characteristics identifying you remaining anonymous, but our privacy policy will apply, and it will be treated as your personal data, if this information is linked to you personally.

This information may also include: data inputted into forms and field; registrations for any accounts, forum, feedback mechanism, social functionality, newsletters or other features of our site; usernames and passwords, log-in / out history, and settings; actions taken within any account or other registration, including view and update and changes to settings; and posts to any forum, feedback, review or other social functionality on our website.

9.           How we collect or generate your personal data

This section sets out ways in which we may collect or generate personal data concerning you.

9.1         Visiting our website

By visiting and using our website you or your computer may provide personal data. This includes: information that is automatically provided by your browser to our servers; information recorded on our web servers about your interaction with our website and pages viewed; information we capture or place on your computer or generate using cookies or other technologies on our website; and information you input into forms and fields on our website. 

9.2         Data you provide

Your personal data will include data you provide (or later amend), whether: from correspondence with you; verbally to us over the phone or in person; by filling in any field or form on a website; by filling in any printed form we provide you; by e-mail; from documents you provide us; and from updates to information provided from time to time.  This includes when you: register or subscribe for any service, account, members, or loyalty program, or make an enquiry or booking  for a vacation or other travel services whether in person, by phone, through our website or otherwise; send us your comments or suggestions; subscribe to any newsletter or other publication; or request sales or advertising information, including brochures. 

9.3         Data obtained from third parties

We may obtain personal data concerning you from third parties, including: providers of vacations, accommodations, other travel services which are enquired about or booked, and their intermediaries; credit, fraud, identity and other searches we may undertake, including searches with public records and regulatory and private organizations; from any business or organization you are associated with; and telephone numbers identified by the telephone system when you telephone us.

9.4         Data generated by us

We and any suppliers or sub-contractors working for us may generate personal data relating to you, including in connection with responding to and dealing with any enquiry, booking or complaint; or in performing any booking or other contract with you; or through analysis of your personal data or data gained from your use of our website. We may record telephone calls with you when lawful to do so.

10\.         What do we use your personal data for ?

This section sets out the uses which we make of your personal data.  We use your personal data to:

10.1      Operate our website

Operate and provide the search, booking, accounts, review, forums and other services, facilities and functions of our websites.  This includes managing accounts or registrations you have with our websites and making changes to your settings and profile at your request.

10.2      Provide information and respond to enquiries

Provide information to you about our website, systems and services, including to respond to booking enquiries and searches for vacations and travel, and keep you updated generally.

10.3      Bookings and other contracts

Enable you to make bookings, and to fulfill, provide, perform, administer, manage, and enforce all bookings,  orders, and other contracts which relate to you (including if you are a passenger in a booking made by someone else), and process transactions authorized or made with us which relate to you.

10.4      Payments

Collect and make payments due and administer our accounts.

10.5      Communication with customers

Communicate with you concerning enquiries, bookings, travel services provided, problems and complaints, and respond to submissions, enquiries or requests from you.

10.6      Record Keeping

Keep internal records and maintain reasonable archives, including as to enquiries, bookings, contracts, travel services, and complaints. 

10.7      Manage and Improve our business

Analyze, audit, provide, operate, administer, maintain and improve our business, website, systems, and services; carry out surveys and analyze the results; run promotions and competitions; undertake product or customer research/development; assist us in and help us improve sales, editorial, advertising and marketing processes; carry out other business development and improvement activities; and provide training to our staff, sub-contractors and suppliers. For example, we may use your personal data to help us profile how customers generally use our websites and book travel services with (or through) us. We may also use this information to ascertain interests so we can better tailor our business offerings.

10.8      Direct marketing

Carry out direct marketing to you.  See next section below for further information.

10.9      Advertising

Report aggregate information concerning usage of our websites to our advertisers. For example, we may create anonymous statistical data about browsing actions and patterns, without identifying any individual.

10.10   Cooperation with government, police and judicial authorities

Provide information in response to a command or request from a government, police or judicial authority. This could include, by way of example, a government agency, police department, or court that either requires or asks us to voluntarily cooperate in providing information for their investigation of any matter or for purposes of a pending proceeding. 

10.11   Anything you specifically consented to

For any purpose which we obtained your consent to.

11.       Use of your personal data for direct marketing

We do not use or disclose your personal data for direct marketing purposes unless we obtained your consent, such as through an opt-in or opt-out tick box on any form or website of ours.

11.1      Direct marketing by us

Where you consented, we may use your personal data to carry out direct marketing and send you marketing messages, materials, adverts and promotions relating to travel services we provide or which are offered by or which can be booked with third parties through us or through any other company in the same group of companies as us (i.e. within The Travel Corporation group) or third parties selected by us. 

You will be free to withdraw your consent at any time, by contacting us as detailed in this privacy policy or as detailed in any direct marketing you receive.  For example, our instructions may state that to unsubscribe, send us an e-mail stating "unsubscribe" in the subject heading.

11.2      Direct Marketing by Third Parties

Where you consented, we may disclose your personal data which is contact data (such as name, e-mail, postal address, telephone, mobile or fax number) to any other company in the same group of companies as us (e.g. within The Travel Corporation group), or to third parties.  They may use this to carry out direct marketing and send you marketing materials, adverts and promotions relating to products and services they offer or which can be booked through them. You will be free to withdraw your consent to our disclosure of your personal data for this purpose, by contacting us as detailed above. Withdrawing your consent will not affect any disclosures we already made (i.e. we will not be able to remove your personal data from anyone we disclosed it to), but we will tell you who they are on request, and you can contact them directly.

12.       Disclosure of your personal data

We transfer your personal data to third parties in the following circumstances:-

12.1      Credit Checks etc.

We may disclose your personal data to third parties (including intermediaries) to carry out checks concerning you or enforce a booking or contract with you (including credit, security, fraud and identity checks).  This may include credit reference agencies and other companies for use in credit decisions, for fraud prevention and to pursue debtors.

12.2      Bookings and performance of contracts 

We disclose your personal data to third parties (including intermediaries) to deal with a booking enquiry made by or for you, to make a booking requested by or for you, to perform and administer a booking for you or other contract with or in respect of you.  This may include; to apply for visas on your behalf, collect payments to be made by you, investigate and respond to complaints, and enforce a booking or other contract with you. Such third parties may include suppliers or sub-contractors and their agents (e.g. airlines, coach, ferry or train companies, hoteliers, hire companies, cruise companies, tour operators etc.).

12.3      Suppliers of travel and other services

We may disclose your personal data to any third party (e.g. supplier, contractor sub-contractor) we make enquiries with or engage or sub-contract to perform a booking or other contract, including to provide any travel, tour or other products or services we agreed to provide to you. We may disclose your personal data to suppliers with whom we make an enquiry concerning or book travel or other products and services for you as agent (whether as agent for you, someone representing you, or the supplier), such as a tour operator. Details of any third party tour operators or other third parties who will be responsible for or supply you travel services booked or enquired about, may be obtained from us on request, and may be stated in any tour or other brochure provided by us. 

12.4      Insurance

If an application is made through us for travel or other insurance to cover you, we will pass your personal data to the insurer.  Information provided by you may be put on to a register of claims and shared with other insurers to prevent fraudulent claims.

12.5      Business Function Outsourcing

Where we use third parties to host, provide, operate or supply any part of our websites, databases, systems, business, or services, or carry out on our behalf any of our business functions or actions (including sending mail, processing payments, providing marketing assistance, providing customer and advertising analysis, and providing customer services), we may provide your personal data to them for use for or processing as part of those purposes. 

12.6      Public forums etc.

Where a facility on our website is designed to make certain of your personal data public (e.g. posts you make to a public forum or review of a facility) then personal data you provide in relation to that forum or facility, which is provided in circumstances indicating it is intended to be published, will be disclosed to the public. 

12.7      Legal requirements

We may supply personal data to a government authority or regulator, police authority, court or party in litigation, where requested to cooperate with the authority or required to comply with a legal requirement, for the administration of justice, for purposes of customs, visas and immigration, or where reasonably required to protect your interests or enforce any booking or other contract.  We may disclose your personal data where otherwise required by or permitted by law.  

12.8      Direct Marketing by third parties

We may disclose your personal data to third parties to carry out direct marketing to you, where you have given consent, to third parties to carry out direct marketing.  See the direct marketing section above.

12.9      Customer Representatives

If our customer is a business or organization, and we hold your personal data in your capacity as an associate of that business or organization (including as agent, representative, contact, employee, officer, owner, partner, or director), we may disclose to them that personal data.   If our customer is making a booking or booking enquiry on your behalf, with your authority, then we may disclose to our customer your personal data as reasonably required in connection with such booking or enquiry, or the subsequent performance of or payment for any booking made.

12.10   Business acquirers

If our business is ever transferred to a third party, your personal data will be transferred to the acquirer to enable them to continue our business.  If we investigate or negotiate a possible transfer to a third party, your personal data may be transferred in the process of investigating the possible transfer. 

13.       How third parties will handle your personal data

Where we provide your personal data to a third party one of the following two circumstances will apply:-

13.1      Processing on our behalf

In some cases, your personal data may be held and processed by them on our behalf.  Then we will remain responsible for what they do with your personal data, and your personal data will be held and processed by them in accordance with our instructions and this privacy policy. 

13.2      Processing on their own account

In other cases, your personal data may be provided to them to be held and processed by them in their own right and on their own account.  In such case, they will have their own responsibility for that personal data, subject to their own privacy policy, and we will not be responsible for what they do with it following disclosure. 

14.       Location of your personal data

We (and any affiliate, subcontractor or other person processing your personal data on our behalf) may transfer, store and otherwise process your personal data anywhere in the world. 

Where we disclose your personal data to third parties, the disclosure may involve transfer of your personal data anywhere in the world, and the third parties may transfer, store or otherwise process that information anywhere in the world. 

We intend to comply with legal requirements concerning the transfer of your personal data by us to any third party outside the country where we are established, and where your personal data is still controlled by us or is being stored or otherwise processed on our behalf, our security measures (as detailed below) will also apply.

15.       Keeping your data secure

15.1      Our security measures

15.1.1      Security Measures

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures with a view to security of personal data.

15.1.2      Transmissions between your web browser and our servers

We use Secured Socket Layer (“SSL”) software to encrypt personal information you provide us while it is in transit over the internet. This will work if your browser is SSL enabled (which most are). You can verify that this is working by looking for the symbol of a closed lock or solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window, and checking that the prefix for the web address in the browser address bar has changed from “http” to “https”. 

15.1.3      Storage of your personal data

Personal information we collect from you online is stored by us and/or our service providers on databases protected through a combination of physical and electronic access controls, firewall technology and other reasonable security measures. 

15.2      Your security measures

For your privacy protection, you should maintain anti-virus and other malware protection software on your computers and other devices, and maintain other measures and follow other procedures to protect your personal data.  You should not include sensitive personal data in any e-mails you send us, including payment card information. 

We encourage you to be careful about whom you give personal data to. Regarding sensitive personal data, such as payment card information, or passport numbers or log-in details, we will only ask you for such information in person or through our website, or by telephone in connection with a booking you make or made. If you are ever in doubt about who is contacting you, asking for information, or why, please do not provide the information. Instead, contact us directly to inquire about the request for information. Please let us know if someone purports to contact you in other circumstances, using our name.

16.       How long do we keep your personal data for ?

We keep your personal data as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes for which we use it, and if longer, for any duration required by law, and for statutory claims limitation periods where your personal data may be relevant to a possible obligation or liability we may have.

17.       Your Rights

Our privacy policy is not intended to create a contract or form part of any contract. You have certain non-contractual rights under the laws noted above, which we mention below. If you contact us about these rights, we may ask for proof of your identity before we act, and may refuse to act if you do not provide this or your identity is not established by you. 

17.1      Access to your personal data

You may ask us to tell you whether we are processing personal data about you, to tell you what personal data we are processing and for what purposes, and to provide you a copy of your personal data that we hold. We may charge a fee for handling your request, in an amount prescribed by law. The law allows us, in certain cases to refuse your request, and we will advise you at the time if this is the case. 

17.2      Use causing substantial distress or damage

You have the right to ask us to stop using your personal data for any purpose in any manner that causes you or is likely to cause you unwarranted and substantial damage or distress, subject to exceptions. 

17.3      Use for direct marketing

You have the right to ask us to stop using your personal data to carry out direct marketing to you. 

17.4      Correction of inaccuracies

You have the right to ask a court to order us to rectify, block, erase or destroy any inaccurate personal data we hold about you.

17.5      Compensation

You have the right to claim compensation for damage and (in certain cases) distress you suffer if we do not comply with the laws referred to above.

17.6      Complaints to applicable authority

The laws we comply with are regulated by the State of California Department of Justice.  In addition to your rights above, if you have a complaint or concern, you can seek assistance from such government regulator, who has powers to compel us to comply with laws and fine us for non-compliance. Before you do so, we hope you will contact us first to discuss any complaint or concerns you have.  

18.       Changes to this privacy policy

We may change this privacy policy at any time and from time to time without notice to you, including by publishing a new version on our website. You should check this privacy policy for updates each time you visit our website to be aware of changes.  You should check the top of the document to see the latest version in force. 

19.       Applicable Law and Disputes

This policy is subject to the law of the state of California, County of Orange[], and you must bring any claims against us exclusively in the courts of the state of California, County of Orange.[England and Wales].

End of Document
